

FRANCIS LAGARES

Full Stack Developer

CONTACT

+34 626 581 624

✓ francis.lagares@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/francislagares

francislagares/github.com

TECH SKILLS

- JavaScript TypeScript
- NodeJS Express NestJS
- React Redux Next.js
- MongoDB Postgres
- RESTful API GraphQL
- AWS / Docker / Kubernetes

SOFT SKILLS

- Problem-solving.
- Teamwork.
- Communication.
- Detail oriented.
- Organization and time management.

LANGUAGES

- English (Professional C1)
- Spanish (Native)

PROFILE

Passionate Full Stack Developer with 4+ years of experience with the MERN stack who enjoys doing both Front-end development and Back-end work as well. Experienced with all stages of the development lifecycle. Well-versed in numerous technologies, highly organized, detail-oriented, and have strong communication skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FRONT END DEVELOPER

BUILD&DEPLOY SL.

May 2023 · Jul 2023

- Development of new UI features using React, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript & REST API.
- Translating designs and wireframes into high quality code.
- Integration with headless CMS for content authoring with a RESTful API.
- Optimizing components for maximum performance across multiple devices and browsers.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Primion Technology GmbH

Feb 2023 - Apr 2023

- Working on enterprise distributed system under Clean Architecture with the NestJS framework, PostgreSQL., TypeORM and RabbitMQ.
- Implemented secure authentication and authorization solutions.
- Writing optimized complex queries with TypeORM.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Ultimate AWS Certified
 Developer Associate 2023 NEW
 DVA-C02
- Docker & Kubernetes: The Practical Guide
- NestJS Modern TypeScript Back-end Development
- Microservices with NodeJS and React
- Complete React Developer in 2020 · w/ Redux, Hooks, GraphQL
- Node.js, Express, MongoDB & More: The Complete Bootcamp 2020
- The Complete JavaScript Course 2020: Build Real Projects
- Advanced CSS and Sass: Flexbox, Grid, Animations and More!

WORK EXPERIENCE

JAVASCRIPT NODE.JS DEVELOPER

Ciklum

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

- Working on web crawlers to gather data across retailers.
- Improve data acquisition software built with NodeJS and TypeScript.
- · Research and monitor the gathered statistics.

BACKEND NODE.JS DEVELOPER

iNuba

May 2022 - Jun 2022

- Writing server-side application logic in JavaScript.
- Connecting external applications and manage exchange of data with Socket.io.

FRONT END / FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Coinscrap Finance

Aug 2021 - May 2022

- Development & Maintenance of React apps to keep them optimized.
- Automated E2E Testing with Playwright.js.
- Working closely with agile team of web developers and CTO.

EDUCATION

INFINITE LEARNING

2019 - CURRENT

Continuosly learning and upgrading skills in Full Stack Development, NodeJS, Express, NestJS, JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJS, Redux, Next.js, GraphQL, MongoDB, Prisma, etc. to stay always in the cutting edge!

RECENT PROJECTS

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Marvel App - () Github Link

Apr 2024

 Next.js 14 Application that uses Marvel API to display data information about various characters.

FRONT END DEVELOPER

GameHub - () Github Link

May 2023 - June 2023

 React Web Application that makes use of the popular RAWG Video Games Database API.